ZAIBA CONTRACTOR

Email: zaiba.contractor@gmail.com

Mob: **+91-9819038344**

Career Goal

Having spent almost a decade in Software Engineering space providing designing, programming, test, delivery and support for various software projects in multiple domains, I am looking to get back to a role as a Technical Lead/SCRUM Master. I have a sound understanding of the Software Development Lifecycle and have had the opportunity to work in different profiles as a developer, system analyst, qa-automation and L3 Support. Apart from this I believe I have good communication skills, having delivered Software Trainings, both within the organization for colleagues and also externally, for working professionals and Engineering graduates. I have had the chance to mentor and manage small technical teams working in Agile Mode. I aspire to add value where there is a new product development and lead a team towards meeting the goals.

Work Experience

Total Experience	11 yrs	
JAVA/J2EE Experience	10 yrs	
Role	Team Lead, Application Developer, Quality Analyst, System Analyst	
Certifications	SCJP 5.0 Certified Programmer, SCWCD 5.0 Certified, Currently pursuing AWS certification	

Companies worked for:

<u>Currently: upskilling myself in latest Web Technologies – REACTJS and DevOps. Also doing</u> freelance work for EdTech Teaching Platform – Techmentry.

Neebal Technologies Pvt Ltd (March2021 to May2022) Technical Owner

Ven2ray India Pvt Ltd (June 2019 to Feb 2020) Technical Lead

Kossine Learning Pvt Ltd (August 2017 to March 2018) as Java Trainer

JP Morgan India Pvt Ltd (December 2015 to May 2017) as Associate (Software Developer)

Adappt UK Ltd. (April 2014 to August 2014) as Technical Lead Web

JP Morgan India Pvt Ltd (March 2011 to January 2014) as Application Developer

Atos Origin (August 2007 to Feb 2011) as System Analyst

Educational Qualification

Bachelors in Engg in Information Technology from Sardar Patel Coll of Engg Mumbai University (2003 – 2007)

H.S.C. from Mithibai College of Science Maharashtra Board (2001 – 2003)

I.C.S.E from Maneckji Cooper Education Trust School (1989 – 2001)

Technical Skills	Technical Skills		
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux.		
Databases	Oracle 10g, MS SQL Server 2005, Sybase.		
Programming Languages	Core Java/J2EE, Java8, Unix Shell, HTML/CSS, Javascript, JEXL Expressions, Basic Python		
Web Technologies and Frameworks	Spring Boot, Spring Batch, AngularJS 4, Vaadin, Spring 4.0, Struts, JSP, Servlets, XML, Html, JAXB, Java Webservices, Hibernate, EasyMock, JMS, Maven, Ant, Documentum, Apache POI, JSON, REACTJS		
Application Servers	Weblogic 9.2, WebSphere Community Edition, Tomcat 5.5, GlassFish ESB, JBoss-SOA 5.0.		
Tools and Utilities	GIT Server, Jenkins, Visual Source Safe, MyEclipse, Subversion, TOAD, HP Quality Centre, Rational Clear Case, Rational ClearQuest, CVS, Toad.		
Test Automation	Test Complete, GreenLight (JP Morgan In-House Automation Tool built in Java, JSON, Angular JS)		

Organizations

Organization: Neebal Technologies Pvt Ltd (March 2021 - April 2022)

Worked as a Technical Owner for various Java/J2EE projects in the company. My responsibilities comprises of Technical Analysis, Designing, Detailed High Level Design Documentation, Project Estimations, Scrum Master, and Reviewer. Project deliveries follow the Agile Methodology and my responsibilities was to lead the team towards project deliveries. Have delivered projects related with Spring, Hibernate, SpringBoot, Containerized Application Development, Unit Testing and well-versed with Java 8 platform.

Organization: Ven2ray Technologies Pvt Ltd. (June2019 - February2020)

Worked as a Software Engineer Lead for their Client–Crexendo. https://www.crexendo.com/. Crexendo is a Telecom Company having Cloud Based Phone Systems and top provider for Internet Telephony to large Corporations in the US. Their products range from VOIP enabled phones, software for Call Centers, Mobility App, desk phone, softphone, video conferencing, and screen sharing to audio conferencing and analytic tools to drive customer business.

I worked as a Software Lead in Backend Services (Java / J2EE, Spring 4.0, Hibernate,

Java Webservices). Had ownership of the Client Dashboard that managed all the customer accounts and Desk / Soft phones as well as Client Onboarding for Call Centers. Led the delivery remotely from Mumbai for the Client.

Technology Stack: Frontend – Angular JS / Javascript, Spring, Java, Hibernate. GIT Server for Code Control. MS SQL Database.

Organization: Neebal Learning Pvt Ltd. (August 2017 to January 2018)

Working as a Java/J2EE Trainer for Kossine. Have delivered instructor led classes for basic Core Java course for Engineering Students, as well as Advance Java Courses for Fresher passouts and Masters Students. Worked mainly as Online Trainer on their Bloombench platform. Also, consulted the organization for performing a Quality Analysis check for the Bloombench product. Provided consulting for their DevOps goals like implementing a GIT Server, creating a JIRA Server instance and creating a POC for automated testing using Selenium.

Organization: JP Morgan India Pvt Ltd. (Dec 2015 to May 2017)

Project Title	GRep -Global Reporting
Team Size	9
Duration	December 2015 to May 2017
Role	Quality Analyst, Functional Testing and Automations Developer
Functional Domain	Cash and Equities
Framework & Technology	Spring 2.0, Apache POI, Apache JEXL, JXLS, Quartz Framework with CRON expressions, Core Java, JMS, Sybase 5.1, Unix and Shell Script.
Project Description	GRep is a Reporting Solution for JP Morgan's Global Cash Equities Trading Applications. It is the Tactical Solution for Front Office, Middle Office Applications to generate following Reports: Client Reporting Regulatory Reporting Summary Flow Reports Reconciliations GRep supports JEXL Expression language. Server Side Technologies involves JMS with EMS server queues, Apache POI, and JXLS.

Organization: Adappt (April 2014 to August 2014)

Project Client	Moreover Technologies
Team Size	6
Designation	Technical Lead- web for Newsdesk Moreover
Framework &	Java 1.7, Spring 3.0, Hibernate, Backbone JS, Google Web
Technology	Toolkit, Web services. Maven for build.
Project Description	Moreovers Newsdesk is a service used by companies for Media
	Monitoring, Market Research and Enterprise wide news sharing.
	Newsdesk gives <u>information</u> professionals, <u>marketing</u> ,
	and corporate communications teams a powerful set of tools to
	turn unstructured mass media into actionable media
	intelligence that can be shared across the organization.

Organization: JP Morgan India (March 2011 to January 2014)

Project Title	DealWorks – Banking and Research (IB)
Team Size	20
Client	JP Morgan
Duration	May 2012 to January 2014
Role	Application Developer
	Working on Requirements with the Bankers and Business
	Analysts. Design, Develop, Test, Deploy and Support Production.
	Interact with Offshore team and work in collaboration.
Functional Domain	Investment Banking- Deal Lifecycle of M&A, IPO, FPO, Tranches
Framework &	Spring 3.0, Hibernate, JPA, Vaadin, Apache CXF, Apache Camel,
Technology	Documentum, JMS, SQL Developer, Oracle 10g, Maven, Ant.
Project Description	Dealworks is a Deal and Document Life Cycle Management
	Application at JP Morgan that is used by all Bankers to create,
	update and maintain Deals and all the related Legal and
	Compliance documents.
	It is also a Document Management System used by various
	departments at JPMorgan. Right from the deal team creation to
	the deal documents getting approved from the conflicts
	department to the Finance and Sponsorship of the deal and the
	KYC to the Legal and Compliance. The whole deal is managed in
	DealWorks. There is a lot of communication and data sharing
	between dependent systems managed within JPMorgan. It is a
	Global application with 8,000 users.

Project Title	Production Infrastructure and Control(IB)
Team Size	6
Client	JP Morgan
Duration	March 2011 to April 2012
Role	Application Developer in Tools and Automations.
Functional Domain	Cash and Equities
Framework & Technology	Struts 1.2, Spring 2.0, Sybase 5.1, Tomcat 6.0, Unix and Shell Script, Apache Zookeeper.
Project Description	The Environments team of Cash and Equities handles the Production Releases of all the application suites under Cash and Equities. My role in the Tools and Automations team was to automate the activities done by the Environments team that would increase their efficiency. Under this role my contribution has been in the Design and Development of an Inventory for the team to keep a track of all the Servers, Environments and Database Activities managed by the team. I am also involved in an Application Infrastructure Modelling Initiative to provide application level plumbing/artifacts to be deployed on servers as a suite of applications. Also working on development of a FIX Monitoring Tool that is used for Validating and Alerting errors in FIX Log messages.

Organization: Atos Origin India (August 2007 to March 2011)

Project Title	Occupational Health
Team Size	12
Client	Atos Medical Services UK
Duration	Oct 2010-March 2011
Role	Senior Developer, Designer

Framework	&	JMS, JBoss-SOA 5.0, Spring 3.0, MS SQL 2000, MySQL, EasyMock
Technology		2.5, XMLBeans 2.4, Maven.
Project		The project is a migration for the occupational health applications of
Description		UK from FileNet to JBPM Workflow. Have worked on JMS
		Configuration and Business Logic for Migration of OH Application from
		.Net to Java Frameworks.
		Have introduced EasyMock Unit Testing Framework and Build
		Strategy for the project in Maven.

Project Title	Spring/Alpha
Team Size	8
Client	Atos Origin UK, France, Germany, Netherlands
Duration	May 2009 - Sept 2010
Role	Team Lead, Coding, Designing and Support. Worked extensively with Global Counterparts. Instrumental in plugging in Webservices for interaction with other Purchase and reporting systems.
Framework & Technology	Java/J2EE, Struts, Webservices, HTML, JavaScript, JSP, Servlets, YUI, MS-SQL Server2005, Tomcat 6.0, Eclipse (D2I), SVN, ClearQuest, ClearCase.
Project Description	The Alpha/Spring Application is a web based application that is used by AO(Europe) employees for claiming their expenses (Expense Module), raising purchase requests (Purchasing Module), booking travel (Travel Module), choosing their flex options (Reflex Module), claiming extra work hours (Special Payment Module) and maintaining the changes in their contract (Staff Variation Module).

Project Title	AVF (Avantix Freedom)
Team Size	4
Client	UK RAILWAYS, Heathrow Express, National Express
Duration	Aug 2008 to April 2009
Role	Enhancement and Support, Built a POC for PDF Ticket Generator, Conducted Inhouse trainings for Spring Framework for colleagues and team members.
Tools & Technology	Spring 2.0, EJB 3.0, Java Webservices, Struts 1.2, Weblogic 9.2, MyEclispse 5.5, HTML, JavaScript, JSP, Servlets, MS-SQL Server2005, Apache Web Server.
Project Description	The AVF System is a routing and processing engine designed to deliver tickets of varying description to a mobile phone via an agreed business process, a process known as m-Ticketing. Retail partners will send AVF ticket information of varying formats, to process and deliver. It performs operations like registration of handsets, Sending tickets, and Cancel tickets, Resending tickets, generating barcode and reporting operations. We also send same ticket information as e-Tickets
Project Title	CORPUS
Team Size	4
Client	UK RAILWAYS
Duration	Sept 2007 to July 2008
Role	Enhancement, Support and Offshore Transition
Tools	Struts-1.2. JSP, Eclipse 3.2, WebSphere Application Server,
&Technology	Oracle10g, JAXB 2.0, JavaScript
Project Description	The system called CORPUS (Codes for Operations, Retail and Planning–a Unified Solution) is a web-based user interface. It will be used by UK Government Officials for standardization of UK Railways, Retail, Planning and Operation codes. Corpus will be initially
	5

populated with current codes from client systems. Corpus will supply codes to modern systems as they are developed. Corpus will support the current legacy batch interfaces to External Systems. There are certain sets of coding structures that are maintained collectively under a single process. These sets of data are used as reference data within the rail planning, operations, and retail functions, and are therefore required to retain consistency across each functional area.